

Nguyen Thi Thuy Anh

Merchandiser

Take many years of experience in sales assistant, customer service and accounting knowledge. I want to look for advancement opportunities in these fields where I will dedicate my ability to contribute to the development of the company and also a place for me to have a sustainable career advancement.

PROFILE

16-09-1987

E.

30- Hoa Long - Lai Thieu Thuan An - Binh Duong

EDUCATION

HO CHI MINH INDUSTRY AND TRADE COLLEGE

MAJOR: ACCOUNTING

2008 - 2011

Learn accounting knowledge about manufacturing businesses and practical accounting skills using Excel spreadsheets.

SKILLS

COMMUNICATION

Good communication skills, developed and accumulated over many years of working in customer service.

ENGLISH

Working in a foreign company environment for many years. I have the ability to receive information and work by English well.

COMPUTER

I am proficient in office software: word, excel, powerpoint.
Especially the ability to work with excel spreadsheets is good. I have worked with global Oracle software for many years.

TIME MANAGEMENT

Ability to divide and organize time to complete multiple tasks at the same time.

TEAM WORK

Ability to work with diverse colleagues, share ideas, support and contribute to the overall goals of the department

PROBLEM SOLVING

Ability to analyze situations, find solutions and make sound decisions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jan, 2021 - Sep, 2024

ANH NGUYEN TECHNICAL SERVICE LTD..

CUSTOMER SERVICE MANAGER

- Price management: manage price list of all customers, make new price/ price adjustment and send the quotation to customers as the request from customers.
- Orders management: receive orders from customers and contact the factory for production planning, contact the warehouse to check inventory and schedule shipment.
- Release delivery notes, invoices by Misa system and contact carrier to arrange delivery.
- Sales contract management: update customer informations, requirements and agreement terms and draft sales contracts for both parties to sign, stamp, track and archive.
- Team management: divide the customer list to monitor each area, observe and evaluate the team's capacity and assign members to manage the appropriate customer list.
- Keep hotline and contact of current customers to follow up and meet all of their demands/requirements regarding: introduce services and products, complaint, testingreport...
- Make timekeeping and payroll for company employees.
- Make monthly sales report and cost report.

Jul, 2012 - Dec, 2020

SHERWIN-WILLIAMS (VIET NAM) LTD.,

* SALES ADMIN

- Price management: manage price list of all customers, make new price/price adjustment and send the quotation to customers as the request from customers or Sales Manager and enter the Oracle system.
- Support Sales Manager to control the overtime situation of the technical team and make timekeeping and payroll for the technical team.
- Support the Sales team to do monthly forecast demands of the customer.
- Follow up finishing process: make the finishing processes, ensuring all the finishing processes are tested and approved by R&D department before running production at customer sites.
- Follow up inventory and distribute equipments, tools and safety equipments for technicians.
- Check and summary the expenses incurred in the month of the team to submit for payment: costs for forwarder to pick up the goods, shipping costs, other costs...
- Make weekly/monthly sales report send to Sales Manager.
- Updating ISO documentation for the Sales department.
- Manage company hotline: receive all hotline calls from customers to introduce products, consult prices, complaint, testingreport... and then send customer's requirements to Sales Manager or KeyAccount Manager.

* SENIOR CUSTOMER SERVICE

- Orders management: receive orders from customers and enter the Oracle system, contact the production department for production planning, contact the warehouse to check inventory and schedule shipment.
- Release delivery notes and invoices are forwarded to the warehouse and arranged to schedule delivery.
- Making customs declaration for import and export containers trading with Singapore and Malaysia and tracking vessel schedules for cargo containers.
- Price management: manage price list of all customers, update new price/adjusted price into the Oracle system as request from Sales department.
- Sales contract management: update customer informations, requirements and agreement terms from the Sales department and draft sales contracts for both parties to sign, stamp, track and archive.
- Receive and handle complaints from customers

Jun, 2011 - Jun, 2012

PHAN THI THANH TUYEN

Sherwin - Williams (Viet Nam) Ltd.,

Sales Manager

Mobile:

Email:

TOA PAINT (VIET NAM) LTD.,

CUSTOMER SERVICE STAFF

- Order management: Receive orders from distributor and enter the system, contact the warehouse to check inventory and schedule shipment.
- Release delivery notes and invoices are transferred to logistic for shipment.
- · Receive and handle complaints from customers.

POORS & AWARDS 2020 2013 Sale Practical Best Improvement Employee at Sherwin- Williams (Viet Nam) 2011 English Communication Perferences REFERENCES HONORS & AWARDS 2013 Best Improvement Employee at Sherwin- Williams (Viet Nam) (Viet Nam)